<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://catchfire.show/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://catchfire.show/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-09T16:14:16-05:00</updated><id>http://catchfire.show/index.xml</id><title type="html">Catch Fire Show</title><subtitle>Zoom past archetypes to find your prototype.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Our Last Dance, Part 1</title><link href="http://catchfire.show/episode/2020/05/26/last-dance-p1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our Last Dance, Part 1" /><published>2020-05-26T21:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-26T21:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://catchfire.show/episode/2020/05/26/last-dance-p1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://catchfire.show/episode/2020/05/26/last-dance-p1.html">&lt;p&gt;Episode 2 is about archetypes and why they are failing us. Catch Fire Show is about moving past our archetypes to define your prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/show_img/002/pic02.jpg&quot;  alt=&quot;blog img&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Episode 2 is about archetypes and why they are failing us. Catch Fire Show is about moving past our archetypes to define your prototype. We all love archetypes. For example, many people, when they’re younger might aspire to be a teacher, pharmacist, fireman, or lawyer. These archetypes seem tangible, and I believe they are currently failing us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to think about this years ago, when I was coaching people and continued when I was teaching at the university level. For me, then where the real rubber met the road was when I became a foster adopt dad of teenagers and my wife and I started to discuss what it looked like for them to launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/show_img/002/pic03.jpg&quot;  alt=&quot;blog img&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After working with professionals that have come out of university, after teaching at the university level, and now looking to prepare my kids to go into the world and become adults, I don’t believe college as a milestone, as a season of life, is now robust enough to encompass all of our kiddos becoming adults. And I don’t think talking about college as the season of life is the way we can best help our kids anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I look back at my story, I’m not convinced that college is where I learned how I want to contribute. And so, we’re not saying college is bad, but we want to work on a framework. We’re calling it a contribution model that is more universal, so it can work with college and without college, that college could be a piece of that model for certain people, but not a mandatory piece of it for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/828834349&amp;color=ff5500&amp;hide_related=true&amp;show_comments=false&amp;show_teaser=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/catch-fire-show&quot; title=&quot;Catch Fire Show&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;Catch Fire Show&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/catch-fire-show/002-our-last-dance-part-1&quot; title=&quot;002 - Our Last Dance, Part 1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;002 - Our Last Dance, Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Core" /><category term="Archetypes" /><summary type="html">Episode 2 is about archetypes and why they are failing us. Catch Fire Show is about moving past our archetypes to define your prototype...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PRESS RECORD</title><link href="http://catchfire.show/episode/2020/05/21/press-record.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PRESS RECORD" /><published>2020-05-21T21:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-21T21:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://catchfire.show/episode/2020/05/21/press-record</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://catchfire.show/episode/2020/05/21/press-record.html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the catch fire show, podcast about zooming in past the archetypes to the prototype. We want to get past all the “shoulds” to your passion and how you want to serve others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/show_img/001/pic05.jpg&quot;  alt=&quot;blog img&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we welcome Daniel Fitzpatrick to the show. Daniel is a friend and founding member of We Are Root Mod. One of the reasons I asked Daniel to join us today is because musicians are a great example of zooming past an archetype to a prototype. Currently I live in St. Louis, Missouri and there’s a rich history of music and specifically jazz here in St. Louis as Daniel and I will talk about later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/show_img/001/pic02.jpg&quot;  alt=&quot;blog img&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miles Davis for example, is from what we call The East Side and I say that affectionately to give credit where credit’s due. Miles Davis is one of my favorite musicians and with all of his baggage, warts, and glory he probably changed jazz forever. Kind of Blue and other songs standout as epics that I listen to often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/show_img/001/pic04.jpg&quot;  alt=&quot;blog img&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you know anything about Miles’ or his music, you understand that, no matter how great of a musician that you are, you can’t tell someone that you will be Miles Davis. That’s not possible. Similarly, as we’re trying to define how we fit into the world, we can’t just pick an archetype any longer and say, I want to be this and have that be the way that we communicate what we want to do. We have to get specific about who we want to be– more specific then choosing an archetype or a hero. We have to zoom in further…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/825440092&amp;color=ff5500&amp;hide_related=true&amp;show_comments=false&amp;show_teaser=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/catch-fire-show&quot; title=&quot;Catch Fire Show&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;Catch Fire Show&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/catch-fire-show/001-danielfitzpatrick&quot; title=&quot;001 - Press Record with Daniel Fitzpatrick&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;001 - Press Record with Daniel Fitzpatrick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Creative" /><category term="St Louis" /><summary type="html">Today we welcome Daniel Fitzpatrick to the show. Daniel is a founding member of We Are Root Mod. One of the reasons I asked Daniel to join us today is because musicians are a great example of zooming past an archetype to a prototype...</summary></entry></feed>